Parsa Khayatzadeh | Resume

pk525@cornell.edu

Position: Ph.D. Student in Systems Engineering, Cornell University

Supervisior: Prof. Michael Charles

Research Area: Computational Sustainability parsakhay.com/research

Research Interset: IAMs, Human-Earth Systems, Shared Socioeconomic Pathways, Sustainable Computing

Summary

I have started my Ph.D. at Cornell as a Systems Engineering student under the supervision of Prof. Michael Charles. I am interested in design aspect of human-earth models. I link different modules of the system to provide a narrative of plausible futures of the world. My current research focuses on the downscaled study of IAMs aimed to serve tribal governed communities and my case study is Navajo Nation.

Education

Ph.D. in Systems Engineering - Ithaca, NY

Aug. 2023 - Present

Ithaca NY

- Area: Computational Sustainability
- Advisor: Prof. Michael Charles

B.Sc. in Industrial Engineering - Tehran, Iran

Aug. 2018 - Jul. 2022

- Advisor: Prof. Hossein Iranmanesh
- Final Project: PV vs. CSP: a solar renewable technology review and electricity cost analysis based on improvised LCOE
- Course Highlights: Operations Research System Analysis Engineering Statistics Fundamentals of Probability Microeconomic Theory Macroeconomics Statistical Quality Control Decision Analysis

Academic Experience

Research Assistant - Cornell University

Aug. 2023 - Present

- Advisor: Michael Charles
- Downscaled Integrated Assessment models

Teaching Assistant - Cornell University

Aug. 2024 - Dec. 2024

- Professor: Natalie Cápiro
- Engineering Processes for Environmental Sustainability

Teaching Assistant - University of Tehran

Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2022

- Courses: Simulation Principles - Probability and Applications - Microeconomics - Macroeconomics - System Analytics

Summer Research Intern - UT's Research Institute for Energy Management and Planning

Aug. 2021 - Jul. 2022

- A feasibility study of solar technologies with a focus on CSP technologies \mid Supervisor: Dr. Hossein Iranmanesh

Extracurricular Activities

Scientific Association of Industrial Engineering at University of Tehran - UTIESA

Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2021

- Board Member
- Managing Editor of Fankaav Stident Journal
- Award: Harekat, University's best student journal in 2022

parsakhay.com - github.com/parsakhay